toastedballs.com 2015-12-29

# Toasted Balls - Privacy

Any words in capitals and/or defined in the Toasted Balls _[Terms of Services](http://www.toastedballs.com/terms)_ of which this Privacy and CookiesPolicy forms part shall have the same meaning as the one given to them in the said Terms of Services.

Although most changes are likely to be minor, the Company may change this Privacy and Cookies Policy from time to time, and in the Company's sole discretion. The Company encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to this Privacy and Cookies. Your use of the Site after any change in this Privacy and Cookies Policy will constitute Your acceptance of such change.

If you have any questions about this Privacy and Cookies Policy or the Site in general, please [contact us](http://www.toastedballs.com/contact).

## Privacy Policy

The Company takes your privacy very seriously and is committed to being transparent with how it uses Your information.

This privacy policy, which has been adapted from a policy originally provided by [Automattic](http://automattic.com/) ([WordPress.com](http://www.wordpress.com/)) under a _[Creative Commons Share-Alike License](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/)_ , describes how the Company treats the information it collects when You visit and use the Site. Please read this notice very carefully.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, the Company collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. The Company's purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how the Site's visitors, users and/or subscribers (generically referred to in this Privacy and Cookies Policy as "visitor" or "visitors")use the Site. From time to time, the Company may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

The Company also collects Personal Data (Personal Data, Data Controller and Data Processor shall have the same meaning as in the Spanish Organic Law 15/1999, on Personal Data Protection - the Data Protection Law-) such as Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on the Site. The Company only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses Personal Data as described below.

### Gathering of Personal Data

Certain visitors to the Site choose to interact with the Site in ways that require the Company to gather Personal Data from them in which case the Company will be deemed as being the Data Controller of such Personal Data. The amount and type of information that the Company gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, visitors who sign up at _[the Site](http://www.toastedballs.com/)_ are asked to provide a username and email address. In each case, the Company collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor's interaction with the Site and/or the Company. The Company does not disclose Personal Data other than as described below and visitors can always refuse to supply Personal Data, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site-related activities or from using the Services.

### Aggregated Statistics

The Company may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to the Site. For instance, the Company may monitor the most popular collections on the Site. The Company may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, the Company does not disclose Personal Data other than as described below.

### Protection of Personal Data

The Company discloses Personal Data only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it (as Data Processor) on the Company's behalf or to provide services available at the Site, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using the Site, you consent to the transfer of such information to them as set out under the section "Transfer of Personal Data". The Company will not rent or sell Personal Data to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, the Company discloses Personal Data only when required to do so by virtue of the Law or by virtue of an order from a competent court or competent public authority. If you are a registered user of the Site and have supplied your email address, the Company may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what's going on with the Site and/or the Company's products and/or services, which the visitor expressly consents. The Company primarily uses its various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so it is expected that this type of email will be kept to a minimum. If You send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users but no Personal Data will be disclosed along such publication. The Company takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of Personal Data.

### Business Transfers

If the Company, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that the Company goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of the Company may continue to use Your Personal Data as set forth in this policy.

### Links to Third Party Sites

This Privacy and Cookies Policy only applies to information collected by the Company through the Site. It does not apply to the practices of companies that the Company does not own or control, or employees that the Company does not manage. The Site may contain links to third party websites. Any information You provide to, or that is collected by, third-party sites may be subject to the privacy policies of those sites, if any. We encourage you to read such privacy policies of any third-party sites you visit. It is the sole responsibility of such third parties to adhere to any applicable restrictions on the disclosure of your personally-identifying information, and the Company and its affiliates shall not be liable for wrongful use or disclosure of your personally-identifying information by any third party collected from you by such third party or acquired by such third party from any source other than the Company.

### Security

All non-personally-identifying information, potentially personally-identifying information and Personal Data described above is stored on restricted database servers.

### Choice/Opt-out

By submitting your email to the Company through the Site and agreeing to be bound by the Terms of Service of the Site, of which this Privacy and Cookies Policy forms part, you consent that the Company may use such email address to send you information concerning new products or services provided by the Company or any commercial information. You may opt not to receive this kind of emails. You may do so by contacting with the following email address: _[contact@toastedballs.com](mailto:contact@toastedballs.com)_. In any case, any email sent to You which contains commercial information will contain an email address or link which you will be able to use in order to opt out from receiving commercial communications via email.

### Transfer of Personal Data

By using the Site you agree that Your Personal Data Gathered by the Company through the Site will be transferred to the following entities and for thefollowing purposes:

### Processing of Your Personal Data

By using the Site you agree that Your Personal Data gathered by the Company through the Site will be used and processed by the Company in the manner and for the purposes set forth in this Privacy and Cookies Policy in order to manage Your use of the Site and the Services. Your Personal Data will be processed in strict compliance with the provisions of Spanish Data Protection Laws applicable from time to time

### Your Rights concerning Your Personal Data

You may exercise your rights of access, rectification, erasure and objection by sending written request to _[contact@toastedballs.com](mailto:contact@toastedballs.com)_. Any request for the exercise of the said rights must comply with the requirements set forth with Spanish Organic Law 15/1999 on Personal Data Protection and the Regulation which develops it, approved by Royal Decree 1720/2007. Those requirements are primarily set forth under article 23 and the following ones of the Regulation of Development of the Personal Data Protection Law approved by Royal Decree 1720/2007.

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. The Company uses cookies to identify and track visitors and their behaviors, their usage of the Site, and their access preferences.

Cookies may be classified under one or various of the following categories in accordance with their purposes:

  * _Analysis cookies_ : These cookies, whether used by the Company or by third parties, allow us to quantify the number of visitors of the Site and to perform measurements and statistical analysis of the use made by visitors of the Site and the Services. We use them to analyze Your browsing of the Site in order to improve the Site and the Services. 
  * _Technical cookies_ : These cookies, whether used by the Company or by third parties, are used enable communication between Your equipment and the equipment of the Site, such as those used to enable the functionality of media players for displaying content or flash content, or such as those used to remember items placed by You on a virtual shopping cart should such functionality be offered in the Site. 
  * _Customization cookies_ : These cookies, whether used by the Company or by third parties, allow us to offer You an access to the Site which is tailored in accordance to certain predefined parameters based on the settings or characteristics of Your equipment such as for instance language settings or characteristics, type of browser used to access the Site, location, etc. Customization cookies may also be used to allow You to request that the Site remembers certain parameters on your behalf such as remembering your language preferences or Your user account so as to prevent you from having to resubmit your log in credentials in subsequent browsing sessions. 
  * _Advertising cookies_ : These cookies, whether used by the Company or by third parties, allow us to manage the advertising spaces in the Site in the most effective way possible based on several criteria such as the frequency at which the ads are displayed. 
  * _Behavioral Advertising cookies_ : These cookies, whether used by the Company or by third parties, allow us to manage the advertising spaces in the Site in the most effective way possible by means of tracking Your behavior through the continuous monitoring of your browsing habits and allowing us to develop a specific profile tailored to such browsing habits which is then used to serve You ads based on the said profile. 

Based on how long they last before they are removed from Your computer, those cookies can also be _session cookies_ , which are erased from Your computer when the browsing session expires or _persistent cookies_ , are stored on Your computer during more than a single browsing session until their expiration date is reached.

The Company uses the following cookies on the Site for the purposes set out before depending on the category to which they belong:

PHPSESSID

Session

The PHPSESSID cookie is native to PHP and enables websites to store serialised state data. On the Action website it is used to establish a user session and to pass state data via a temporary cookie, which is commonly referred to as a session cookie. As the PHPSESSID cookie has no timed expiry, it disappears when the client is closed.

Session

>__ga (Analysis cookies)

2 years or update

Cookie set by analytics.js; JavaScript library belonging to Google. The analytics.js library is part of Google Universal Analytics and uses this source cookie that contains an anonymous identifier to distinguish users.

Third Party

__gat (Analysis cookies)

10 minutes or update

Cookie set by analytics.js; JavaScript library belonging to Google. The analytics.js library is part of Google Universal Analytics and uses this source cookie that contains an identifier sessions is used to throttle the amount of requests that are available to be made.

Third Party

FVS_SHOW_COMMENTS

1 day or update

This cookie is used to know if comments have to be shown or not.

FVS_UNREGISTERED_VOTED_USER_ID

10 years or login

Cookie storing a identifier generated randomly for those who are not logged in to be able to track votes and visits for them.

REMEMBERME

1 year or update

Cookie set to be able to remain the users logged in.

**Exoclick** :

__utma

__utmc

__utmz

impressions (Advertising cookies)

11 months or update

Session

6 months or update

24h

These cookies are used to collect data about the websites and individual pages that users visit both on and off our websites (which might indicate, for example, your interests and other attributes). They are typically used to deliver advertisements that are more relevant to you and your interests, and to help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign. This information is shared with other organizations such as advertisers and our partners, who might use it with information about how you use other websites, including to identify shared interests and behaviors across groups of users who visit our (and other) websites.

Third Party

**Disqus** :

__utma

__utmb

__utmc

__utmt

__utmz

disqus_unique

disqusauth

sessionid

(Technical Cookies)

1 year or update

24h

Session

24h

6 months or update

1 year or update

1 month or update

1 month or update

To post comments and have your Disqus login information remembered across pages, cookies - specifically, first party (and in some browsers, third-party) cookies - must be enabled.

Third Party

You can choose to allow, block or delete cookies installed on Your equipment by adjusting the settings of Your browser. Given the huge amount of browsers and versions thereof currently present in the market, the Company cannot provide You with technical assistance on the process of blocking or deleting cookies in each of them. For that purpose, You might need to consult with the developer of Your browser or check the user guides and support guides provided by such developer.

Without prejudice to the foregoing, and only for informative purposes, we provide you with the following links to the websites of the developers of the most popular browsers in the market which offer information on how to manage cookies on their respective browsers:

  * Safari: _<http://support.apple.com/kb/PH19214>_
  * Firefox: _<https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences>_
  * Chrome: _<https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en>_
  * Internet Explorer: _<http://windows.microsoft.com/is-IS/windows7/How-to-manage-cookies-in-Internet-Explorer-9>_
  * Opera: _<http://help.opera.com/Windows/11.50/en/cookies.html>_

We make no representations as to whether the information contained in the links above will be available at all times or that it will be accurate or suitable for You.

If you continue to browse the Site after visualizing the relevant disclaimer warning you of the use of Cookies in the Site, that action will be taken as your acceptance to the use of the cookies listed above.
